RUSIRU THUSHARA

372/1, Opalla, Govinna, Horana, Sri Lanka

+94 71 302 2214

🗖 thusharakart@gmail.com 🏻 rusiru.me 📮 github/thusharakart 📑 linkedin/rusiru-thushara

PROFILE

A 3rd-year computer engineering undergraduate with five national level hackathon wins since 2019 and over two years of software development in Java and Python. A quick learner with a strong interest in algorithmic programming, artificial intelligence and a passion for finding simple, innovative solutions to complex programming problems and seeking an opportunity in a challenging environment for an internship to contribute towards the organization and team growth.

EDUCATION

University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

Nov. 2017 - Present

Undergraduate in BSc. Engineering(Hons.) Computer Engineering CGPA: 3.80/4.00

Taxila Central College, Horana, Sri Lanka

2008 - 2016

G.C.E. Advanced Level Examination | Physics - A, Combined Mathematics - A, Chemistry - B

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Team Lead | SternX Engineering (Pvt) Limited

March. 2021 - Present

Developing Web and Mobile Applications for clients, Team Leader of an eight member team

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Python, Java, Java Script, C/C++, Matlab

Web Development

Django, Express, React, Spring Boot, Flask, HTML/CSS

Machine Learning and Data Modeling

TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas, OpenCV

HONORS & AWARDS

1st Runner up of Douthan 1.0

Feb. 2021

12 hour competitive programming competition for university undergraduates in Sri Lanka.

Organizer: IEEE Student Branch, NSBM Green University, Sri Lanka

1st, 2nd, 1st Country Rank in Hack the Interview IV, V, VI (Asia Pacific)

2020

60 hours competitive coding contest on hackerrank

Placed 1st, 2nd, 1st country rank and 88th, 343th, 195th respectively in Asia Pacific region

2nd Runner up of HackDown 2020

Apr. 2020

Competitive programming competition for university undergraduates in Sri Lanka.

Organizer: IEEE WIE Student Branch Affinity Group of University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka.

2nd Runner up of hackStat 2.0

Oct. 2019

Competitive programming competition for university undergraduates in Sri Lanka.

Organizer: Stat Circle, University of Colombo, Sri Lanka.

2nd Runner up of UoJCoders v1.0

Mar. 2019

12 hour competitive programming competition for university undergraduates in Sri Lanka.

Organizer: Department of Computer Science, University of Jaffna, Sri Lanka.

Gold Medal in Sri Lankan Physics Olympiad | National Rank - 2nd, Score: 96/100

2016

An annual competition held among high school students to select delegations for the APhO and IPhO.

PROJECTS

Swarm Robots Platform 2021

Obstacle bots that are localized with an overhead camera setup with the capability of positioning themselves without collisions forming challenging patterns.

Technologies: Python, OpenCV, Numpy, Three.js, CSS, HTML, MQTT, GRPC Techniques: Stochastic gradient descent, PID, Image processing, Encryption

Project MESOW Ongoing

A portable device for the visually impaired, which is getting a video stream of the surrounding, analyses it and sends a real-time acknowledgment of the surrounding via voice.

Technologies: Python, OpenCV, Numpy, AI, NLP

National Covid 19 Management System

Ongoing

Full-stack web application showcasing country level, district level, hospital level, and overall patient statistics of daily Covid-19 updates and the patient management system.

Technologies: Spring Boot, React, PostgreSQL

Airport Ticket Booking System

2020

Web application and Mobile Application with a Database Management System for passengers and airports.

Technologies: Dart, MySQL, PHP, HTML, CSS

Crossword Puzzle Game

2021

An instant game developed for Facebook focusing children where they can select and solve a crossword puzzle.

Technologies: React

Auction Server 2019

Implemented a sample server that can be used by clients to bid for items in a stock exchange.

Technologies: Java | Techniques: Threads, Synchronization primitives, Sockets, OOP, and Collections

CERTIFICATES AND COURSES

Introduction to Cybersecurity Cisco Networking Academy	Jan. 2021
Data Structures and Algorithms Specialization UC San Diego Coursera	Aug. 2020
Deep Learning Specialization deeplearning.ai Coursera	Aug. 2020
Al for Medicine Specialization deeplearning.ai Coursera	Aug. 2020
AWS Computer Vision: Getting started with GluonCV AWS Coursera	Aug. 2020
Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching	2019 - 2020
Routing and Switching Essentials, Introduction to Networks Cisco Networking Academy	

Fundamentals of Business Economics | Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA) May 2019

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Instructor and Teaching Assistant | University of Peradeniya

2020 -Present

CO321: Embedded Systems for 3rd year Computer Engineering undergraduates

CO253: Programming and Networking for Electrical and Electronic Engineering undergraduates

GP106: Computing for all first year undergraduates

Data Structures and Algorithms with Hackers' Club for all undergraduates at UoP | Volunteer

Maths, Science and English for students of Omaththa College, Mathugama. | Volunteer

2019 - 2020

2020

REFERENCE

Prof. Roshan Ragel roshanr@pdn.ac.lk Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Computer Engineering Faculty of Engineering, Univeristy of Peradeniya

Dr. Isuru Nawinne <u>isurunawinne@eng.pdn.ac.lk</u> Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Computer Engineering Faculty of Engineering, Univeristy of Peradeniya